=== C:/Users/erick/Downloads/2018CLINICALDIETMANUAL.pdf pages 479 ===
[sodium]
 - ral and Parenteral Nutrition Modifications for Gastrointestinal Disorders Modification in Sodium Diet Fat Controlled Diet Diets for Renal Disease Test Diets Sharon Braun, MS, RDN CDE Dietary Management of Diabetes Mellitus Shannon K. Du
 - ar J – 13 Consejos para Cocinar (Healthy Cooking Tips) J – 17 SECTION K: MODIFICATIONS IN SODIUM Sodium Restricted Diets K – 1 Use the Food Labels to Compare Products K – 3 DASH: Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (1,500 mg or 2,40
 - 13 Consejos para Cocinar (Healthy Cooking Tips) J – 17 SECTION K: MODIFICATIONS IN SODIUM Sodium Restricted Diets K – 1 Use the Food Labels to Compare Products K – 3 DASH: Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (1,500 mg or 2,400 mg So
 - ompare Products K – 3 DASH: Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (1,500 mg or 2,400 mg Sodium) K – 4 Guide to DASH Eating Plan -2,000 calories K – 5 Tips to Reduce Salt and Sodium K – 6 Compare Food Labels K – 6 Herbs and Spices K – 
[potassium]
 -  – 1 Dietary Management of Bulimia Nervosa L – 9 SECTION M: MODIFICATIONS IN MINERALS Low Potassium Diet (2,000 mg) M – 1 High Potassium Diet (4,000 mg) M – 4 Low Oxalate Diet M – 7 -- 9 of 479 -- Table of Contents 5 SECTION N: DIETS FOR R
 - rvosa L – 9 SECTION M: MODIFICATIONS IN MINERALS Low Potassium Diet (2,000 mg) M – 1 High Potassium Diet (4,000 mg) M – 4 Low Oxalate Diet M – 7 -- 9 of 479 -- Table of Contents 5 SECTION N: DIETS FOR RENAL DISEASE Diets for Renal Disease 
 - y Nutrient Recommendations for Renal Disease N – 4 Table N – II: Average Protein, Sodium, Potassium and Phosphorus Values N – 5 Procedure for Calculating a Renal Diet N – 6 Sample Renal Diet Prescription 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,0
 -  Renal Diet N – 6 Sample Renal Diet Prescription 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium, 1,000 mg Phosphorus N – 8 Basic Renal Patterns 40 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium N – 9 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,
[phosphorus]
 - ommendations for Renal Disease N – 4 Table N – II: Average Protein, Sodium, Potassium and Phosphorus Values N – 5 Procedure for Calculating a Renal Diet N – 6 Sample Renal Diet Prescription 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium
 - mple Renal Diet Prescription 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium, 1,000 mg Phosphorus N – 8 Basic Renal Patterns 40 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium N – 9 60 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,000 mg Potassium N – 
 - rotein N – 25 2,000 Calories 60 gm Protein N – 26 2,000 Calories 80 gm Protein N – 27 Low Phosphorus Diet N – 28 Renal Diet in Spanish/Dieta Renal N – 30 SECTION O: DIETS FOR HEPATIC DISORDERS Nutrition Therapy for Liver Disease O – 1 SECTI
 - women Sodium 2300 mg per day for both men and women Potassium 4700 mg/d for men and women Phosphorus 700 mg/d for men and women Folate 400 mcg/d for men and women. Iron 8 mg/d for men and women. Magnesium 420 mg/d for men and 320 mg/d for 
[renal]
 -  for Gastrointestinal Disorders Modification in Sodium Diet Fat Controlled Diet Diets for Renal Disease Test Diets Sharon Braun, MS, RDN CDE Dietary Management of Diabetes Mellitus Shannon K. Duffy -Goff, MPH, RDN, CNSD Clinical Nutrit
 -  mg) M – 4 Low Oxalate Diet M – 7 -- 9 of 479 -- Table of Contents 5 SECTION N: DIETS FOR RENAL DISEASE Diets for Renal Disease N – 1 Fluid Restriction N – 3 Table N – I: Selected nutritional parameters for varying levels of kidney fai
 - iet M – 7 -- 9 of 479 -- Table of Contents 5 SECTION N: DIETS FOR RENAL DISEASE Diets for Renal Disease N – 1 Fluid Restriction N – 3 Table N – I: Selected nutritional parameters for varying levels of kidney failure. Daily Nutrient Rec
 - ional parameters for varying levels of kidney failure. Daily Nutrient Recommendations for Renal Disease N – 4 Table N – II: Average Protein, Sodium, Potassium and Phosphorus Values N – 5 Procedure for Calculating a Renal Diet N – 6 Sam
[diabetic]
 - – 26 Plate Method for Meal Planning D – 27 Management for Pre-gestational and Gestational Diabetic D – 28 Calculating the Diet for Pregnancy D – 30 Gestational Diabetes Meal Planning Grid D – 32 Blood Sugar Goals – Pre-gestational and GDM
 - otassium N – 10 80 gm Protein, 2,000 mg Sodium, 2,500 Potassium N – 11 Renal Diet for the Diabetic Patient N – 12 Food Exchange Lists for Renal Diet for Diabetic Patient N – 13 Basic Diabetic/Renal Meal Plan 1,500 Calories 60 gm Protein N
 -  N – 11 Renal Diet for the Diabetic Patient N – 12 Food Exchange Lists for Renal Diet for Diabetic Patient N – 13 Basic Diabetic/Renal Meal Plan 1,500 Calories 60 gm Protein N – 22 1,500 Calories 80 gm Protein N – 23 1,800 Calories 60 gm 
 - betic Patient N – 12 Food Exchange Lists for Renal Diet for Diabetic Patient N – 13 Basic Diabetic/Renal Meal Plan 1,500 Calories 60 gm Protein N – 22 1,500 Calories 80 gm Protein N – 23 1,800 Calories 60 gm Protein N – 24 1,800 Calories 
[cardiac]
 - dementia Thiamine deficiency Protein Thiamine, niacin, B12, pyridoxine deficiencies Heart Cardiac enlargement Pitting edema – bilateral Protein deficiency Protein (albumin <2.5–3.0 g/dl), thiamine, vitamin C deficiencies Skin Skin Dry, s
 - xcessive fluid intake; Rapid refeeding; Catabolism of lean body mass with potassium loss; Cardiac, hepatic, or renal insufficiency Monitor I & O Assess fluid status daily Monitor body weight daily Weight change >0.2 kg/day reflects decre
 - gical complications can include lowered body temperature, decreased muscle mass including cardiac muscle spasms, dehydration, hair loss, bruising, delayed sexual development, and lanugo (a downy growth of body hair), or even death. Other
 - bnormal red cell, white cell, and platelet function, central nervous system disturbances, cardiac dysfunction, and rhabdomyolysis. The risk of these occurring rapidly with the use of TPN is greatest in patients with chronic weight loss, 
[dysphagia]
 - l Soft/Soft Chopped Diet B – 6 Pureed Diet B – 7 Nutritional Management for Patients with Dysphagia B – 8 SECTION C: PEDIATRIC NUTRITION Determination of Kcal and Protein Requirements C – 1 Infant (0 – 12 Months) C – 3 Toddler and Preschoo
 - tion B: Modifications in Consistency and Texture Nutritional Management for Patients with Dysphagia General Principles Dysphagia or difficulty swallowing can be caused by any lack of coordination in the complex act of swallowing and result
 - istency and Texture Nutritional Management for Patients with Dysphagia General Principles Dysphagia or difficulty swallowing can be caused by any lack of coordination in the complex act of swallowing and result in aspiration. The ability t
 - t involves moving foods and liquids from the mouth to the stomach in an efficient manner. Dysphagia may be characterized by a variety of symptoms such as feeling of “choking,” coughing frequently during or after meals or drinking liquids, 
[texture]
 - nabel, MS, RDN, CNSC Diana Chen, MS. RDN Normal Nutrition Modification in Consistency and Textured Calorie Controlled Diet Enteral and Parenteral Nutrition Modifications for Gastrointestinal Disorders Modification in Sodium Diet Fat Cont
 - rition A – 17 Nutrition and Alcoholism A – 19 SECTION B: MODIFICATIONS IN CONSISTENCY AND TEXTURE Clear Liquid B – 1 Post-Operative Diet B – 2 Full Liquid/Blenderized Diet B – 3 Tonsillectomy and Adenoidectomy (T&A) Diet B – 5 Mechanical
 - ch World 13(3):219-227, 1989. -- 42 of 479 -- Section B. Modifications in Consistency and Texture B - 1 Clear Liquid Diet Indication Used as a transition from NPO to a liquid or solid diet. This diet is used for the pre and post surgical
 - l protein and calories. -- 43 of 479 -- B - 2 Section B: Modifications in Consistency and Texture Post-Operative Diet Indication Used as a transition from NPO to a solid diet for the surgical patient to minimize post-operative nausea and
[allergen]
 - difications for Gastrointestinal Disorders Gluten-free label reading tips: Under the Food Allergen Labeling and Consumer Protection Act of 2004, if a food or an ingredient contains wheat or protein from wheat, the word “wheat” must be cle
[portion]
 - uttered or sweetened foods to allow the child to experience the natural taste of foods. o Portion sizes, texture and consistency are adjusted for age, individual appetites and preferences. As a general serving size guideline, offer one t
 - ages 5-11 years, with no dietary modifications. Description Diet is same as regular diet. Portion sizes are adjusted according to age of child. Nutritional Adequacy This diet is nutritionally adequate if vitamin D fortified milk is used.
 - rs with no dietary modifications. Description Diet is same as regular diet with increased portions of milk and high calcium foods and additional calories to meet rapid growth requirements and physical maturation as well as increased need
 - tain 9 calories per gram. When carbohydrates are in short supply, fats are released and a portion (called glycerol) can be used to make sugar. Cholesterol is a different type of lipid that is used to make bile acids, vitamin D, hormones 
[serving]
 - d cancer. Description This diet is based on the regular diet supplemented with additional servings of high protein foods such as milk and eggs. Commercial oral nutritional supplements may also be used to provide added protein, calories a
 - l good sources of zinc. -- 19 of 479 -- A - 6 Section A: Normal Nutrition Zinc Amount per serving in mg. Soy foods Soybeans, cooked ½ c. 1.0 Soybeans, dry roasted ½ c. 2.1 Soymilk, ½ c. 0.3 Soymilk, fortified, ½ c. 0.5-1.0 Tempeh, ½ c. 0
 - one (eggs, meat, fish, poultry, dairy products, nuts and many grains). Calcium Amount per serving in mg. Soyfoods Cultured soy yogurt, fortified, ½ c. 367 Soybeans, cooked, ½ c. 88 Soybeans, dry roasted, (soy nuts) ¼ c. 60 Soybeans, gree
 -  males and females ages 71+ years the recommended DRI is 800 IU/day. Vitamin D Amount per serving μg* Cereals, ready-to-eat, fortified, 1 oz. 0.5-1.0 Egg yolk, large 1 0.6 Cow’s milk, fortified, ½ c. 1.2-1.3 Soymilk or other nondairy mil
[fluid]
 - 9 -- Table of Contents 5 SECTION N: DIETS FOR RENAL DISEASE Diets for Renal Disease N – 1 Fluid Restriction N – 3 Table N – I: Selected nutritional parameters for varying levels of kidney failure. Daily Nutrient Recommendations for Ren
 - itamins T – 23 Important Food Sources for Some Minerals T – 25 Calculation of Total Daily Fluid Requirements T – 27 Determination of Reasonable Body Weight for Adults T – 28 Body Mass Index (BMI) Chart T – 29 Suggested Weights for Adul
 - he extra body fat is usually complete by the time the infant is 6 months of age. Adequate fluid intake, rest and family support are essential for successful lactation. 2. Protein requirements are increased approximately 20 gm per day o
 - tion Generally, the diet should be reduced in fat, increased in carbohydrates, and low in fluid content. Small, frequent meals are also recommended. Nutrition Adequacy This diet may not be adequate in all nutrients to meet the Dietary 
[IDDSI]
 - owing is a summary of the new guidelines. For the complete policy and procedure visit www.iddsi.org If adopted for the healthcare facility the complete procedure should become part of the policy and procedures for dysphagia diets and w
=== C:/Users/erick/Downloads/tdm.pdf pages 27 ===
[sodium]
 - …………………………………………… 14 Restricted Fat / Low Cholesterol ……………………………………………………… 15 Restricted Sodium ....…………………………………………………………...……… 16 Gastro-Esophageal Reflux Disease (GERD)………………………………………... 17 Pregnancy and Lactation ………………………………………………
 - ietitian for more information. MODIFIED CONTENT: Controlled A: Enhanced fiber, restricted sodium / fat / cholesterol - Approximately 2,300 calories, <2,300 mg sodium, <215 mg cholesterol, 33 g dietary fiber - Constipation, cardiovascula
 - ed fiber, restricted sodium / fat / cholesterol - Approximately 2,300 calories, <2,300 mg sodium, <215 mg cholesterol, 33 g dietary fiber - Constipation, cardiovascular disease, hypertension, gastroesophageal reflux Controlled B: Same a
 - tension, gastroesophageal reflux and blood glucose control Pro 1A: Restricted protein and sodium - Approximately 2,100 calories, 61 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium - Short term treatment of symptomatic encephalopathy Pro 2A: Restricted prot
[potassium]
 -  - Short term treatment of symptomatic encephalopathy Pro 2A: Restricted protein, sodium, potassium, and phosphorus - Approximately 2,200 calories, 65 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Fai
 -  and phosphorus - Approximately 2,200 calories, 65 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Failure, End Stage Renal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/po
 - d Stage Renal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/potassium/phosphorus - Approximately 2,400 calories, 90 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <4,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - End stage renal dise
 - sium/phosphorus - Approximately 2,400 calories, 90 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <4,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - End stage renal disease and receiving hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Protein controlled diets with comorbidity
[phosphorus]
 - reatment of symptomatic encephalopathy Pro 2A: Restricted protein, sodium, potassium, and phosphorus - Approximately 2,200 calories, 65 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Failure, End Stage 
 - roximately 2,200 calories, 65 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Failure, End Stage Renal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/potassium/phosphorus - A
 - nal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/potassium/phosphorus - Approximately 2,400 calories, 90 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <4,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - End stage renal disease and rec
 - roximately 2,400 calories, 90 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <4,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - End stage renal disease and receiving hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Protein controlled diets with comorbidity of blood glucose imba
[renal]
 - lories, 65 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Failure, End Stage Renal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/potassium/phosphorus - Approximately 2
 - 300 mg sodium, <3,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - Acute Renal Failure, End Stage Renal Failure (ESRF), Nephrotic Syndrome Pro 3A: Moderate protein, reduced sodium/potassium/phosphorus - Approximately 2,400 calories, 90 g prote
 - es, 90 g protein, <2,300 mg sodium, <4,000 mg potassium, <1,000 mg phosphorus - End stage renal disease and receiving hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis Protein controlled diets with comorbidity of blood glucose imbalance order the ‘B
 - tricted protein, sodium, potassium, and phosphorus): used to treat individuals with acute renal failure, nephrotic syndrome, or End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD). 3. Pro 3 (moderate protein, restricted sodium, potassium, phosphorus): used
[dysphagia]
 - Moist texture, easy to chew and swallow - Sore mouth, dental problems, impaired GI tract, dysphagia - An expiration date must be included with the diet request Puree: Foods that are blended until smooth with no visible chunks. These foods 
 - do not require chewing. - Recommended for those with severe swallowing difficulties, like dysphagia Pureed diets are available at RMUs only, consult the regional dietitian for more information. MODIFIED CONTENT: Controlled A: Enhanced fibe
 - ted for individuals with sore mouth, dental problems, impaired gastrointestinal tract, or dysphagia. This diet is often needed for short periods of time; therefore, an expiration date is required with the diet request. DIETARY PROVISIONS/P
[texture]
 - …………... 9 Therapeutic Diet Summary …………………………………………………………… 10 THERAPEUTIC DIETS: MODIFIED TEXTURE / CONSISTENCY Clear Liquid ……………………………………………………………………………... 11 Full Liquid ………………………………………………………………………………. 12 Soft ………………………………………………………………
 - - NYS DOCCS Therapeutic Diet Manual – June 2025 Page 10 THERAPEUTIC DIET SUMMARY MODIFIED TEXTURE / CONSISTENCY: Clear Liquid: Fluids and foods that are clear liquid at body temperature - Pre-op or diagnostic GI procedures, post-op for g
 - ficantly impaired - An expiration date must be included with the diet request Soft: Moist texture, easy to chew and swallow - Sore mouth, dental problems, impaired GI tract, dysphagia - An expiration date must be included with the diet r
 - 25 Page 13 SOFT DIET OBJECTIVE  The objective of the diet is to provide foods of a moist texture that are easy to chew and swallow. DISCUSSION This diet is indicated for individuals with sore mouth, dental problems, impaired gastrointes
[allergen]
 - before eliminating foods from the diet permanently. The following foods are either common allergens or are widely incorporated into the general confinement menu: fish (cod, tuna), tomatoes, onions, corn, milk/dairy, wheat/gluten, soy, egg
 - Attendance Agreement (Form #3273) indicating an allergy to one or more of the common food allergens, food service will eliminate the offending foods with modifications made to the meal plan as necessary. Substitutions are not made based o
[portion]
 -  Agreement, Form 3273. 2. The incarcerated individual shall sign the attendance agreement portion of the Therapeutic Diet Request Form and Attendance Agreement that documents understanding of the meal attendance requirement and intention
 - he new diet request should reflect the complete diet prescription, not just the “changed” portion. The most recent diet request form supersedes all others. 2. A therapeutic diet request is canceled under the following circumstances: A. A
 -  categories entitled Controlled A & B, PRO 1A & B, PRO 2A & B, and PRO 3A & B. 4. “Double portions” of food is not considered a therapeutic diet and is not available. Refer to the Health Services Policy #1.46 on medical nutrition supplem
 - __________________________________________________________ SAMPLE ONE DAY MENU Follow the portion sizes below and use as a guide when making meals. • Breakfast: ½ cup hot or cold cereal; 1 slice whole wheat bread/1 pancake w/1 pc syrup /
[fluid]
 -  June 2025 Page 10 THERAPEUTIC DIET SUMMARY MODIFIED TEXTURE / CONSISTENCY: Clear Liquid: Fluids and foods that are clear liquid at body temperature - Pre-op or diagnostic GI procedures, post-op for gradual transition to a normal diet,
 - sily absorbed by the gastrointestinal tract. DISCUSSION The clear liquid diet consists of fluids and foods that are clear liquid at body temperature. This diet can be used for: pre-operative or diagnostic procedures of the bowel and co
 - e of the diet is to limit sodium intake. DISCUSSION Sodium is critical for maintenance of fluid balance, transmission of nerve impulses and muscle contraction. Sodium may need to be restricted to treat hypertension, cardiovascular dise
 - t hypertension, cardiovascular disease, heart failure, kidney disease or for disorders of fluid imbalance. DIETARY PROVISIONS/PREPARATION INFORMATION A sodium restricted meal plan is obtained by requesting a Controlled A diet. This mea
=== C:/Users/erick/Downloads/Download_Field_Descriptions_Oct2020.pdf pages 17 ===
[portion]
 - Table / File Field Definition of data element Synonyms (used on user interface only) food_portion Discrete amount of food Measures (for foundation or legacy foods), Portions (for survey foods) id fdc_id ID of the food this food portion p
 - ace only) food_portion Discrete amount of food Measures (for foundation or legacy foods), Portions (for survey foods) id fdc_id ID of the food this food portion pertains to seq_num The order the measure will be displayed on the released 
 - undation or legacy foods), Portions (for survey foods) id fdc_id ID of the food this food portion pertains to seq_num The order the measure will be displayed on the released food. amount The number of measure units that comprise the meas
 - sp, the amount is 3). Not defined for survey (FNDDS) foods (amount is instead embedded in portion description). measure_unit_id The unit used for the measure (e.g. if measure is 3 tsp, the unit is tsp). For food types that do not use mea
[serving]
 - roduct. GTIN/UPC ingredients The list of ingredients (as it appears on the product label) serving_size The amount of the serving size when expressed as gram or ml serving_size_unit The unit used to express the serving size (gram or ml) h
 - e list of ingredients (as it appears on the product label) serving_size The amount of the serving size when expressed as gram or ml serving_size_unit The unit used to express the serving size (gram or ml) household_serving_fulltext amoun
 - e product label) serving_size The amount of the serving size when expressed as gram or ml serving_size_unit The unit used to express the serving size (gram or ml) household_serving_fulltext amount and unit of serving size when expressed 
 -  serving size when expressed as gram or ml serving_size_unit The unit used to express the serving size (gram or ml) household_serving_fulltext amount and unit of serving size when expressed in household units branded_food_category The ca
